Guide to the Cornell University examinations, 1869-1931.
Cornell University examinations,
- Series I. Examination Questions - Assorted
  - History - Questions for the use of Historical Students in the University of Michigan, By C.K. Adams - Professor of History, Undated (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; first 3 pages are ripped; date could have been on the front; annotated; 2 parts; Part First: Consitutional History of England (with 14 questions); Part Second: Constituational History of the United States (12 questions); total 16 pages
  - History - Cornell University - Examination in History, Undated (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 14 questions; question 1 begins: "Give briefly and concisely the main causes of the Revival of Learning in Western Europe"; questions on Macaulay's Essays, Essay on Barrre, On Buckle's History of Civilization in England
  - History - Cornell University - Department of History, First Term, Third Year, 1877-12-19 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 14 questions; question 1 begins: "What authority have we for the history of the Romans before B.C. 250?"
  - History - Cornell University - Department of History, First Term, 1878-12-18 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 16 questions numbered with Roman numerals; question I begins: "Into what two branches were the Italici divided?"
  - History - Examination in Modern History, 1878-12-20 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 16 questions; question 1 begins: "Give some account of the way in which procedure by torture was fastened upon Modern Europe"
  - History - Cornell University - Modern History, Close of Second Term, 1879-03-28 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 15 questions; question 1 begins: "Name the main things done by Charles VII in the Centralization of Power"
  - History - Cornell University - Department of History, Third Year, Third Term, 1879-06-11 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 20 questions; slightly annotated; question 1: "Describe geographically Normandy, Guyenne, Brittany, Burgundy, Flanders."
  - Chemistry - The Cornell University - Syllabus of Lectures on Chemistry - Theoretical Chemistry, Inorganic Chemistry, Undated (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 25 questions on Theoretical Chemistry; 5 questions on Inorganic Chemistry; question 1 on Theoretical Chemistry: "Give a definition of chemistry, and explain the distinction between it and physics"
  - Chemistry - Examination in General Chemistry, 1878-06-12 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 10 questions; slightly annotated; question 1: "Mention the important compounds of sodium which occur in nature"
  - Chemistry - General Chemistry, Second Term, 1878 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 9 questions; question 1: "Explain by means of examples the method of determining the formula of a compound"
  - Chemistry - Directions for Bequences in Chemical Practice, Undated (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten directions in purple ink; divided into three parts (I - III); 3 pages; could not completely discern originial title
  - Chemistry - Chemical Equations, Undated (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten guidelines in purple ink; begins: "In writing these equations observe"; 8 parts (I - VIII); 2 pages
  - List of Apparatus, Undated (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten in purple ink; 33 appratus listed; signed at the bottom "G.C. Calchrell, Professor" but name was not fully identifiable
  - Mathematics - Arithmetic - Directions for Exams, Undated (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; note at the top begins: "As the time for reading each paper is in general necessarily very short, your chances of success in mathematical examinations …"; 5 directions; direction 1 begins: "Write legibly, without crowding"
  - Mathematics - Arithmetic, 1876-09-11 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 7 questions; question 1 begins: "Write in figures, using the proper commas and decimal-points, …"
  - Mathematics - Arithmetic, 1877-06-18 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 5 questions; question 1 begins: "Write out the metric tables of length capacity, and weight"
  - Mathematics - Arithmetic, 1877-09-18 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 9 a.m.; 5 questions; question 1 begins: "Write the Metric table of Long Measure"
  - Mathematics - Arithmetic, 1878-01-08 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 9 questions; question 1 begins: "Give the Metric Tables of length, surface, capacity, and weight"
  - Mathematics - Arithmetic, 1878 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 8 questions; question 1 begins: "Write down a prime and also a composite number"
  - Mathematics - Arithmetic, 1878-06-17 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 9 a.m.; 8 questions; question 1 begins "Describe the Roman notation"
  - Algebra, 1876-09-11 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 9 questions; two sheets glued to one page (First Sheet, Second Sheet); question 1: "Multiply a--b into x--y, and give all the reasoning"
  - State of New York - Department of Public Instruction - Examination for State Certificates, Questions in Algebra, 1876-12-21 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; long page, ripped slightly and folded in book; 8 questions; question 8: "Derive the formula for finding the last term of a Geometrical Progression"
  - Algebra - Forenoon (Morning), 1877-06-18 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; questions 1-4; question 1 begins: "Twice A's property and 3 times B's property, are together equal to $8000"
  - Algebra - Afternoon, 1877-06-18 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; questions 5-8; question 5 begins: "Clear the following equation from radicals and solve it"
  - Algebra Through Quadratics [Not for those who are examined in Algebra Entire.] - First Paper, 1877-09-18 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 11 a.m.; questions 1 -4; question 1(a): "Remove the parantheses from …"
  - Algebra Through Quadratics [Not for those who are examined in Algebra Entire.] - Second Paper, 1877-09-18 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 2 (1/4) p.m.; questions 5-9; question 5(a) begins: "Find x, y, and z from the equations …"
  - Algebra Entire - First Paper, 1877-09-18 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 11 a.m.; questions 1-5; question 1(a) begins: "What is meant by a 'negative quantity'?"
  - Algebra Entire - Second Paper, 1877-09-18 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 2 (1/4) p.m.; questions 6-12; question 7(a): "Reduce the following radicals to their simplest forms, and add them …"
  - Algebra, 1877-12-18 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 2 (1/2) p.m.; 8 questions; question 1 begins: "Define 'similar quantities' … Students in the Technical Courses with substitute the following …"
  - Algebra Through Quadratics [Not for those who are examined in Algebra Entire.] - First Paper, 1878-01-08 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 11 a.m.; questions 1-7; question 4(a) begins: "Find the lowest common multiple of …"
  - Algebra Through Quadratics [Not for those who are examined in Algebra Entire.] - Second Paper, 1878-01-08 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 2 (1/2) p.m.; questions 8-11; question 8(a) begins: The length of a room is 2 yards more than the breadth …"
  - Algebra Entire - First Paper, 1878-01-08 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 11 a.m.; questions 1-6; question 4(a) begins: "What is meant by the logarithm of the number n to the base b?"
  - Algebra Entire - Second Paper, 1878-01-08 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 2 (1/2) p.m.; questions 7-10; question 7(b) begins: "The sum of the roots of a quadratic equation equals what?"
  - Algebra Through Quadratics - First Paper, 1878-06-17 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 11 a.m.; questions 1-5; question 1(b) begins: "Perform the operations indicated in the following expression, simplify the result, and divide it by a+x"
  - Algebra Through Quadratics - Second Paper, 1878-06-17 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 2 (1/2) p.m.; questions 1-8; question 1 begins: "Solve the set of equations"
  - Algebra Through Quadratics - First Paper, 1878-09-17 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 11 a.m.; questions 1-5; question 1 begins: "Find the number to which if 3 be added, …"
  - Algebra Through Quadratics - Second Paper, 1878-09-17 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; bottom of page was frayed; questions 1-7; question 1 begins: "Solve the equation …Find the sum of the two roots"
  - Algebra Entire - First Paper, 1878-09-17 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 11 a.m.; questions 1-2, 6; note in the middle of the page: "[Questions 3, 4, 5 as in 'Algebra Through Quadratics']"; question 1 begins: "Write the Binomial Formula, …"
  - Algebra Entire - Second Paper, 1878-09-17 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 2 (1/2) p.m.; questions 6-8; note at top of page: "Questions 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 as in 'Algebra Through Quadratics'"
  - Algebra, 1878-12-17 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 2 (1/2) p.m.; 9 questions; question 9 begins: "Describe the method of finding equal roots of an equation"
  - Algebra - Technical, 1878-12-17 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in purple ink; 9 questions; question 1 begins: "Prove that multiplication is commutative and associative for 2 factors"
  - Algebra Through Quadratics, 1879-01-07 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 11 a.m.; questions 1-7; question 1 begins: "Half of A's property exceeds 1/3 of B's property by $6000"
  - Algebra Entire, 1879-01-07 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 10 (1/2) a.m.; questions 8-13; note at top of page: "Questions 2, 4, 6, and 7 as in 'Algebra Through Quadratics'"; question 8 begins: "Write the logarithm of the expression …"
  - Algebra Through Quadratics, 1879-06-16 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 8 a.m.; Room VII; 10 questions; question 8 begins: "Find two numbers whose sum is 6"
  - Geometry - The Cornell University - Geometry, Undated (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 6 questions; question 1: "A perpendicular is the shortest line that can be drawn from a point to a line"
  - Plane Geometry, 1877-09-18 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 4 p.m.; 5 questions; question 1 begins: "If the opposite sides of a quadrilateral be equal each to each, …"
  - Plane Geometry, 1878-01-08 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 7 questions; question 1 begins: "Define a straight line, parallel lines, a right angle, …"
  - Geometry, 1878-03-26 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 2 (1/2) p.m.; 8 questions; question 1 begins: "Define -- a plane, a straight line perpendicular to a plane, …"
  - Plane Geometry, 1878-06-17 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 4 p.m.; 5 questions; question 2 begins: "Prove that if the diagonals of a quadrilateral bisect each other"
  - Plane Geometry, 1878-09-17 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 4 p.m.; 5 questions; question 1 begins: "Define:--An Angle; A Right Angle; An Acute Angle…"
  - Plane Geometry, 1879-01-07 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 5 questions; question 1 begins: "Define: Parallel Lines; A Triangle; A Right Triangle; …"
  - Solid Geometry, 1875-12-14 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; questions 1-5; questions 6-7 as "Substitutes"; question 1 begins: "Of all isoperimertric polygons having the same number of sides"
  - Solid Geometry, 1877-09-20 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 8 a.m.; 4 questions; question 1: "The sum of any two face-angles of a triedral angle is greater than the third"
  - Geometry - A, 1877-03-21 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 2 pages; 5 questions; last page is annotated; question 1 begins: "From a given point without a plane"
  - Geometry - B, 1877-03-21 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 2 pages; 5 questions; question 1 begins: "Two triedral angles are equal or symmetrical"
  - Solid Geometry, 1878-01-10 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 8 a.m.; 5 questions; question 1 begins: "Any triangular pyramid is the third part of a triangular prism"
  - Solid Geometry, 1878-06-19 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 8 a.m.; 5 questions; question 1: "Define a Plane, a Great Circle, a Pole of a Circle, a Lune."
  - Solid Geometry, 1878-09-19 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 8 a.m.; 5 questions; question 1: "Define:--A Prism, A Zone, A Spherical Triangle, A Trirectangular Triangle"
  - Solid Geometry and Conic Sections, 1879-03-25 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 9 questions; question 1: "Planes perpendicular to the same striaght line are parallel to each other."
  - Plane Analytic Geometry, 1876-12-13 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; initialed L.A.W. at the bottom; 9 a.m.; Sibley Building; 9 questions (I - IX); question I.I: "The length of the side joining the first two points."
  - Plane Analytic Geometry - Technical Courses, 1877-12-17 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 8 a.m.; 6 questions; question 1(a) begins: "Draw carefully an ellipse, and a hyperbola …"
  - Analytical Geometry - Prof. Potter, Undated (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 9 questions; question 1 begins: "Derive the equation of a meridian curve of the earth"
  - Plane Analytic Geometry - Professor Wait, Undated (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 9 questions; question 1: "Explain Peirce's system of angular notation, and show why
  - Analytic Geometry - Peck, 1878-12-18 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 2 (1/2) p.m.; 8 questions; question 1 begins: "Find the equation of the straight line that passes through the points …"
  - Analytic Geometry - Technical Courses, 1878-12-18 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 2 (1/2) p.m.; Sibley Building; 8 questions; question 1(a) begins: "Find the equation of the straight line that passes through the point …"
  - Analytic Geometry - 3 Dimensions, Undated (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 7 questions; question 3 begins: "Write the general equation of planes that contain the above line"
  - Analytic Geometry (An. Geom.) of 3 Dimensions, 1878 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 4 questions; question 1 begins: "Find equation of sphere whose centre is at point …"
  - Cornell University - Descriptive Geometry: Sophomores, Fall Term, 1878-12-16 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten in purple ink; could not completely discern originial title; 8 questions; question 1 begins: "Find the intersection of two cylindrical …"
  - Cornell University - Trigonometry - Professor Arnold, Undated (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 8 questions; question 1: "Give definitions of tangent and secant as ratios, and find tanx in terms of secx"
  - Trigonometry A, 1877-06-12 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 8 questions; question 1 begins: "Express the six trigonometric functions as ratios …"
  - Trigonometry B, 1877-06-12 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 8 questions; question 2 begins: "Given the six functions of an angle, …"
  - Cornell University - Term Examinations - Trigonometry, 1888-06-09 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 8-11 a.m.; 7 questions; question 1 begins: "Find directly from the definitions what are the largest and smallest values each trigonometric function can have …"
  - Plane and Spherical Trigonometry, 1877-09-20 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 10 a.m.; 8 questions; question 3 begins: "Obtain the formula for the cosine of the sum of two angles, and deduce the formula"
  - Plane Trigonometry, 1878-01-10 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 9 (1/2) a.m.; 5 questions; question 1(a) begins: "Define in two ways the secant of an angle"
  - Spherical Trigonometry, 1878-01-10 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 11 (1/2) a.m.; 4 questions; question 1 begins: "Prove that in any spherical triangle …"
  - Trigonometry, 1878-03-26 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 2 (1/2) p.m.; Room K; initialed at the bottom L.A.W.; 5 questions; at the bottom of the page: "(Courses of Arch., Civil Eng., and Math)"
  - Trigonometry, 1878-06-11 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 2 (1/2) p.m.; 2 pages (First Sheet, Second Sheet: "to be worked after handing in answers to the above"); questions 1-6 on First Sheet; questions 7-8 on Second Sheet
  - Plane and Spherical Trigonometry, 1878-06-19 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 10 a.m.; 8 questions; question 2 begins: "Give the algebraic signs of the sine, cosine, …"
  - Trigonometry, 1879-06-10 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 8 questions; question 2 begins: "Make a table showing the signs of the several trigonometric functions for each of the four quadrants"
  - Differential and Integral Calculus, 1876-12-14 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; initialed L.A.W. at the bottom; 9 o'clock; Sibley Building; 9 questions (I - IX); slightly annotated; question II begins: "If from a circular piece of paper with a given radius R, a sector be cut out ..."
  - Differential Calculus and Analytic Geometry of Three Dimensions, 1877-03-20 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; initialed L.A.W.; Room 3 Sibley Building; 2:15 p.m.; 10 questions; 2 pages front and back; question 1 begins: "Give geometrical illustrations showing …"; list of candidates on the last page
  - Integral Calculus - Technical Courses - Loomis, 1877-12-17 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 8 a.m.; 8 questions; question 6 begins: "Prove the formula for the differential of a plane area"
  - Integral Calculus, 1877-12-17 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 8 a.m.; 7 questions; question 1 begins: "Prove Eddy's formula for integrating … "
  - Calculus - Winter Term, 1877-1878 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; initialed L.H. Potter at the bottom; 7 questions; question 1 begins: "What is meant by a Differential, …"
  - Differential Calculus, 1878-03-25 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; initialed J.E.O at the bottom; 7 questions; question 1 begins: "What is meant by the limit of any expression?"
  - Differential Calculus, 1878-03-25 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; initialed L.A.W. at the bottom; 6 Sibley; 6 questions; question 1 begins: "What is meant by the Derivative of a function?"
  - Differential Calculus, 1878-06-04 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 11 a.m.; 6 Sibley; slightly annotated; 5 questions; question 1: "Give Cox's demonstration of Taylor's Theorem"
  - Differential and Integral Calculus, 1878-12-16 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; initialed L.A.W; 8 a.m. to 11 a.m.; 6 questions (I - VI); question 1: "Annotate Articles 322 and 323 Differential Calculus"
  - Calculus -- Darres, 1879-03-28 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 9 questions; question 1: "Define The Cycloid, and find its equation"
  - Differential Calculus and Analytic Geometry of Three Dimensions, 1879-03-28 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; initial L.A.W.; 6 Sibley; 8 to 11 a.m.; 7 questions; question 7 begins: "Investigate the form of the surface represented by the equation"
  - A page of equations, Undated (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - Calculus and Analytical Geometry of 3 Dimensions, 1879-03-28 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 8-11 a.m.; 6 Sibley; 2 pages; 9 questions; question 5 begins: "Prove that an equation involving only two coordinates will …"
  - Differential Calculus, 1878-06-14 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 11 a.m.; 6 Sibley; 6 questions; question 6 begins: "Find the minimum value of …"
  - Physics - B - Cornell University - Heat, Undated (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 5 questions; question 1 begins: "Describe the determination of the absolute coefficient of …"
  - Physics - The Cornell University - Heat, Undated (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 11 questions; question 1 begins: "Reduce the following temperatures Centigrade to …"
  - Physics - B, Fall Term, 1874 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; questions 3, 6, 7, 12, 13, 18, 21; question 3: "Define (a) Centre of Gravity and (b) the various kinds of equilibrium"
  - Physics - C, Fall Term, 1874 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; questions 4, 9, 10, 14, 15, 17, 20; question 4: "Define the terms (a) velocity and (b) acceleration"
  - Physics - D, Fall Term, 1874 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; questions I, 2, 5, II, 23, 27, 28; question 28: "How is the velocity of air in a flue to be determined?"
  - Physics - B - Cornell University, Undated (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; "Phil Barnard" written at the top; 5 questions; question 1 begins: "Describe the phenomena of statical induction"
  - Physics - B - Mechanics, Fall Term, 1875 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; questions 1-6 and problems 7-9; question 1 begins: "Define the unit time"